<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alpine Adventures </title>
    <link>http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/post/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Ashok vardhan Viswanadha</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-05-04 23:35:48 -0700 PDT</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Matterhorn Peak, CA</title>
          <link>http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/post/matterhorn-peak/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 23:35:48 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Ashok vardhan Viswanadha</author>
          <guid>http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/post/matterhorn-peak/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Elevation: 12,280ft (3,744 m)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Hoover Wilderness, North Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dates: May4th-5th, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matterhorn peak
MTN3 - Expedition training is last in mountain series courses offered by SMC and i planned to complete it this year. But I missed this because of Nepal trip and luckily got chance in last minute for Free Expedition training by Rob Ritchey May 4th weekend. Been with Rob once for MTN1 and this is my second time with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sierra buttress or Donner peak is the common destination for expedition trainings but Rob chose Matterhorn peak. I have never been to Matterhorn and I heard climbing it is pretty long and strenuous one (~14miles with 5K feet gain one way). Also it&amp;rsquo;s ~6hr drive from bay area given 120 is closed. Woke up at 1:30AM, drove to Roseville to carpool with Rob and Boris (Aconcagua and Denali Summitter who moved to bay area from Sydney). Reached Bridgeport around 8AM and US-395 welcomed us with clouds at eye level and greenery at its best with el nino snow covered Eastern Sierras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/morning.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hoover wilderness seen from Bridgeport, US-395.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/2hr drive towards Mono village and we all set to start our adventure after 6 other frndz joined us. Small introduction, gear check and having a banana and granola we started our adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/lake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Twin Lakes, Mono village.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hike is gradually uphill and we encountered snow after a mile crossing horsecreek falls entering back country. Took a quick stop to recollect our Navigation skills by taking another bearing we walked towards the steep colouirs next to meadow. Climbed a nice colouir by exchanging steps and kicking trail over ankel level snow without crampons and with hiking poles. It was fun exchanging turns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/colouir.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Climbing colouir around 8500ft.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we reached top it started snowing and snow is very soft and knee deep level, making us wear snow shoes to travel further up. We almost reached 9000ft and our bivy spot is 500ft more. Taking nice switch backs we reached bivy  spot showing where we had a clear view of Matterhorns East and West colouirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/switchbacks.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Switchbacks before reaching bivy spot, 9500ft.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picked our spots, setting up our bivy (first time sleeping outside tent and praying no winds), cooked our food and slept. Decided to wake up at 5AM to start around 6AM. Surprisingly its is very pleasant and I had a 5hr continuous sleep. Views of stars when I woke up around 2AM is breathtaking. Woke up at 5:15AM, no wind, clear skies, perfect early morning start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/base-camp-morning.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Early morning view of Sawtooth ridge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started around 6:40AM we took a steep chute next to camp and we walked towards the west of  glacier plateau by sticking flags to track our return in case of whiteout around noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, we decided to do traverse on West instead of crossing the glacier plateau or main ridge line to reach the colouir. Traverse is so spicy that initially it looked scary but later on turned out to be adventurous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/traverse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Spicy traverse on North-west walls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step by step for almost 2hrs we were close to colouir. Ryan kicked all steps and side traverse on rocks is spicy. But still long way to go. 1/2hr later we reached base of colouir and it&amp;rsquo;s complete whipeout. We were at 11,300ft and decided to turn back as it is around 11AM. Also snow is knee deep level and climbing colouir won&amp;rsquo;t be fun. Turned back and again completing the traverse reached camp.. packed everything and headed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/matterhorn/matterhorn-full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Matterhorn with east and west colouirs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took us almost 2.5hrs and we are back at our cars by 3:30PM. Refreshed with coconut water and headed to Bridgeport to grab burgers and to say goodbye to Sierras. Me and Rob discussing about upcoming climbs and his plans for Canada rockies and Peru Cordrillea, we reached Roseville around 10PM and I drove back to bay by 12 completeing 2hrs of Dan carlin Hardcore history &amp;ndash; King of Kings I. Overall hitting back country, sleeping in bivy, Sierras in winter, Traverse on steep slopes turned weekend into another Alpine adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full picture album: &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/photos/xp1qLkeHGUJVAbfw9&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/photos/xp1qLkeHGUJVAbfw9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mt.Whitney, CA</title>
          <link>http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/post/mt-whitney/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 23:35:48 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Ashok vardhan Viswanadha</author>
          <guid>http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/post/mt-whitney/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Elevation: 14,505 ft (4,421 m)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Inyo National Forest, Sequoia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dates: April27th-30th, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After relaxing for 2 week-ends after Nepal Trip, time is back to hit California mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attempted Mt.Whitney via Mountaineers Route with friends from Sierra Mountaineering Club. Freezing temps, stuck in tent for 14hrs and able to reach upto 12,500ft (Check point - Iceberg Lake). An alaskan alpine experience in Sierras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ashokiiit.github.io/ashokiiit.github.io/images/mt-thor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mt.Thor(12,306ft) when returning back.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pics: &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/photos/89bhrt82iMBoDkZY7&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/photos/89bhrt82iMBoDkZY7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
